We want to be able to pick up our collectable
Player ゲームオブジェクトがアイテムと衝突するときに
game objects when our Player game object
それらが取得できるように
collides with them.
したいと思います
To do this we need to detect
そのためにはPlayer ゲームオブジェクトと
our collisions between the
Pickup ゲームオブジェクト間の
Player game object and the Pickup game objects.
衝突を検出する必要があります
We will need to have these collisions
これらの衝突に
trigger a new behaviour
新しいビヘイビアをトリガーさせ
and we will need to test these collisions
正しいオブジェクトを取得していることを
to make sure we are picking up the
確認するために
correct objects.
衝突をテストする必要があります
The Pickup objects, the Player's UFO
アイテム、プレイヤーである UFO
and the walls all have colliders that
壁、すべてがコライダーを持っており
inform us about collisions.
それによって衝突が報告されます
If we didn't test our collisions
どのオブジェクト同士が衝突しているのか
to find out which objects we've collided with
見極めるテストをしないと
we could collect the wrong objects by accident.
うっかり、壁などの誤ったオブジェクトを
We could collect the walls for example.
集めてしまうでしょう
First we need to reactivate our Player.
まず、プレイヤーを再アクティベートする必要があります
Highlight the Player game object
Player ゲームオブジェクトをハイライトし
and click the Active checkbox
アクティブにするチェックボックスをクリックし
to make the player visible once more in the scene.
シーンで再び見えるようにします
Next let's select the PlayerController script
PlayerController コンポーネントで
and open it for editing by double clicking
PlayerController スクリプトを選び
on the script name
その名前をダブルクリックして
in the PlayerController component.
開きます
Just a note, we could edit this script
スクリプトは、そのオブジェクトが
regardless of whether the game
アクティブでもそうでなくても
object is active or not.
編集可能です
Now that we have the script open what
スクリプトを開きました
code are we going to write?
どんなコードを書くべきでしょうか
We could write collider and then search the
コライダーを書き、それからホットキーを使って
documentation using the hot key combination.
ドキュメンテーションを検索することもできます
But there is a different way that we could
しかし、
do this as well.
違うやり方でもあります
Let's return to Unity and look at the
Unity にもどって
details of our Player game object.
Player ゲームオブジェクトの詳細を見てみましょう
What we're interested in here is the
ここで、使えそうなのが
Circle Collider 2D component.
Circle Collider 2D コンポーネントです
In the header of each component on the left
各コンポーネントのヘッダーの左側にあるのは
is the component's turndown arrow,
コンポーネントの折り畳み用の矢印
the icon,
アイコン、使用可能な場合は
the enable checkbox, if it's available,
アクティブ化のためのチェックボックス
and the type of component.
そして、コンポーネントのタイプです
On the right is the context sensitive gear gizmo
右側はコンテキストによって変わる歯車型メニューと
and an icon of a little book
クエスチョンマークがついた
with a question mark.
小さな本のアイコンです
This is what we need.
この小さな本を使用します
This is the quick link to the
これは Unity マニュアルの
component reference in the Unity manual.
コンポーネントレファレンスへのクイックリンクです
If we select this icon we are
このアイコンを選択すると
taken not to the scripting reference
スクリプトリファレンスでなく
but to the component reference in
マニュアルのコンポーネントリファレンスに
the Unity manual.
移動します
We would read this document to find
このコンポーネントの使い方を
out more about how to use this
エディターとの関連でもっと知るために
component in the context of the editor.
このドキュメンテーションを読むこともできます
We however want to find out how to
しかし、知りたいのはこのコンポーネントクラスへの
script to this component's class.
スクリプトの方法です
To do this we simply switch to scripting
そのために、スクリプティングへ切り替えて
and we are taken to the scripting reference
circle collider 2D の
for the circle collider 2D.
スクリプトリファレンスへ移動します
We want to detect and
私たちに必要なのは
test our collisions.
衝突の検出とテストです
For this project we are going to use
このプロジェクトには
OnTriggerEnter2D.
OnTriggerEnter2D を使用します
You'll find this at the bottom of
この項目は、ドキュメンテーションの
the documentation page under
最後の方で
Messages.
Messages の下にあります
Just imagine if we were,
例えば、自分が配管工で
say, a daring plumber and we
素晴らしいお宝のコインを
jumped up to collect a perfect
集めるために飛びあがり
arch of coins and bounced
最初のコインを収集したと思ったら
off the very first one as we
跳ね返り地面に落ちるところを
collected it and fell back to the ground.
ちょっと想像してみてください
Not very elegant.
あまり素敵ではないですね
This code will give us the ability to detect
このコードを使うと
the contact between our Player game object
実際の物理的な衝突なしに
and our Pickup game object
Player ゲームオブジェクトと
without actually creating
Pickup ゲームオブジェクトの接触を
a physical collision.
検出することができます
Click on OnTriggerEnter2D
さらに情報を得るには
to learn more.
OnTriggerEnter2D をクリックしてください
The code example on this page is
このページのコード例は
not exactly what we're looking for
私たちが求めているものにピッタリではありません
but that's okay, we can change it.
しかし、手を加えるので大丈夫です。
First let's copy a portion
まず、このコードの一部を
of this example code.
コピーしましょう
We'll copy from the line
OnTriggerEnter2D 関数の
public bool charcterInQuicksand
public bool charcterInQuicksand から
to the closing bracket of our
それを閉じる括弧まで
OnTriggerEnter2D function.
コピーします
Let's paste this beneath our
これを FixedUpdate 関数の下に
FixedUpdate function.
貼り付けます
Next let's look at this code.
次に、コードを見てみましょう
We're using the function OnTriggerEnter2D.
私たちは OnTriggerEnter2D 関数を使います
OnTriggerEnter2D will be called by Unity
Player ゲームオブジェクトが最初に 2D のトリガーコライダーに接触するとき
when our Player game object first touches
OnTriggerEnter2D は
a 2D trigger collider.
Unity　によって呼び出されます
We're giving as an argument
接触した
a reference to the 2D trigger collider
2D トリガーコライダーへの参照を
that we have touched.
引数として渡します
This is the 2D collider called Other.
これがOther という 2D コライダーです
This reference gives us a way to get
この参照によって
a hold of the 2D colliders that we touch.
接触する2D コライダーを捕えることができます
With this code, when we touch another
このコードで
2D trigger collider we will
他の 2D トリガーコライダーに接触するとき
set the boolean variable
ブーリアン変数 CharacterInQuicksand を
CharacterInQuicksand to true.
True に設定します
This won't change anything in our game,
これによってこのゲームに変化はありませんが
but could be used by another script
他のスクリプトで
to make the Player move slowly, for instance.
プレイヤーをゆっくり動かすためなどに使用できます
For the sake of this lesson
このレッスンでは
we'll use this to do something different.
もっと違う用途で使います
Previously we deactivated the
以前 Pickup オブジェクトを作成したときに
Player object manually in
エディターによって手動で
the editor when we were creating our
Player オブジェクトを
Pickup objects.
ディアクティベートしました
Now we will deactivate
今度はPickup オブジェクトを
our Pickup object via a script.
スクリプトでディアクティベートします
First we can remove the
まず characterInQuicksand 変数を含む
two lines containing the characterInQuicksand variable.
2 行を削除します
Next, how will we deactivate
次に、どうやって Pickup オブジェクトを
our Pickup objects?
ディアクティベートできるでしょうか
Well, what clues do we have?
さて、どんな手がかりがあるでしょう
We can address the other collider's
other コライダーのゲームオブジェクトは
game object through other.gameObject.
other.gameObject として表すことができます
We want to test the other game object
other ゲームオブジェクトをテストして
and if it's a Pickup object
それが Pickup オブジェクトならば
we want to deactivate that game object.
そのゲームオブジェクトをディアクティベートすればいいのです
So let's look up Game Object
それでは、何が見つかるか
with our hot key combination
ホットキーを使って
and see what we can find.
GameObjectを見てみましょう
In the documentation page for Game Object
GameObject のドキュメンテーションのページで
there are a few important items
役立ちそうなアイテムが
that we want.
いくつかあります
The first is Tag.
1 つめは Tag です
Tag allows us to identify the game object
Tag を使うと
by comparing the Tag value
Tag の値と文字列を比較して
to a string.
ゲームオブジェクトを識別できます
The second is Set Active.
2 つめは Set Active です
This is how we activate or deactivate
これは、コードを通じてゲームオブジェクトを
a game object through code.
アクティベート/ディアクティベートする方法です
The last item we need to know about is
最後は
CompareTag.
CompareTag です
CompareTag allows us to efficiently
CompareTag で効率よく
compare the tag of any game object
ゲームオブジェクトの Tag を文字列の値と
to a string value.
比較できます
Let's open up these three items,
この 3 つをそれぞれ別のタブで
each in their own tab.
開いてみましょう
Tag allows us to identify a game object
Tag を使うと、Tag の値で
by a tag value.
ゲームオブジェクトを認識できます
We must declare our tags in the
使用する前にTags And Layers パネルで
Tags And Layers panel before using them.
tag を宣言する必要があります
Once the tag has been declared
tag を宣言したら
we can use this tag in our code.
コードに使用できます
In this example the game object's
この例では、ゲームオブジェクトのtag　は
tag is being set to Player.
Player に設定されます
To test, check, or compare a tag
Tag をテスト、検証、比較するには
there is an efficient built-in way and that
効果的なビルトインの方法があります
is CompareTag.
それはCompareTag です
With CompareTag we can efficiently
CompareTag で、効率よく
compare the tag of any game object
ゲームオブジェクトの Tag を文字列の値と
with a string value.
比較できます
Let's copy the sample code and
サンプルコードをコピーして
paste it in to our working pallet.
スクリプトに貼り付けましょう
Now GameObject.SetActive
今度はGameObject.SetActive です
This is how we activate or deactivate
これは、ゲームオブジェクトを
a game object.
アクティベート/ディアクティベートする方法です
This is the code equivalent of
このコードはInspector の Name フィールドの前にある
clicking the Active checkbox next to
アクティベート用のチェックボックスを
the Name field in the inspector.
クリックするのと同様です
In our case, just like the code snippet,
ここでは、コードスニペッツと同様に
we will call GameObject.SetActive
Pickup ゲームオブジェクトをディアクティベートするために
to deactivate our Pickup game objects.
GameObject.SetActive を呼び出します
Let's copy this code and returning
このコードをコピーして
to our script editor, paste it in
スクリプトエディターに戻り
to our pallet as well.
同じように貼り付けます
I feel we have enough pieces to write our code
コードを書くのに十分な材料がそろったと思います
let's delete the game object
では GameObject を
that we previously typed and let's
削除して
modify the following line to read
以下のように修正します
if (other.gameObject.CompareTag("Pickup")
if (other.gameObject.CompareTag("Pickup")
The Pickup tag has
Pickup タグは
already been defined in the
ダウンロードしたプロジェクトですでに
project that you downloaded.
決められています
But we'll take a look at how to
しかし、ここでは Tags And Layers パネルに
add your own tag to the
独自の Tag を加える方法を
Tags And Layers panel.
見てみましょう
We can also delete the
Destroy (other.gameObject) の行も
Destroy (other.gameObject) line.
削除できます
We are going to add braces
If ステートメントに
to our If statement.
中括弧を加えます
This code will work without braces.
このコードは中括弧なしでも動きますが
Without braces however,
ただし、中括弧がない場合は
only the next line of code is
If ステートメントの次の 1 行だけが
associated with the If statement.
If ステートメントと連動します
All remaining lines of code will be
その他の行は
executed regardless of how the
Ifの条件を満たすかどうかにかかわらず
conditions in the If statement are met.
実行されます
To associate multiple lines of code with
If ステートメントと複数行を
an If statement they must be
関連付けたい場合は
enclosed in braces.
複数行を中括弧で囲みます
For clarity in this case we will
ここでは、明確にするために
enclose our gameObject.SetActive (false) line
gameObject.SetActive (false) の行を
inside a set of braces
1 組の中括弧にいれます
making sure that the code is properly indented.
コードを適切にインデントしてください
Remember, indenting code has
コードをインデントしても
no meaning to the compiler.
コンパイラーにはなんの意味もありません
Creating braces around our code
今、コードの周りに中括弧をつけるのは
now not only makes the association
If ステートメントとの関係を明白にするだけでなく
with the If statement clear,
後のレッスンで
but will allow us to easily update
中括弧で囲んだ部分のアップデートを
this block of code in later lessons.
簡単にするためです
With the script as it's currently written
スクリプトは現状のままだと
we would be setting the Player's game object
Player のゲームオブジェクトを
to Inactive.
非アクティブに設定します
Instead we want to deactivate
代わりに、other ゲームオブジェクトを
the "other" game object.
ディアクティベートする必要があります
So let's change our second line to
そのため、2 行目を
other.gameObject.SetActive (false).
other.gameObject.SetActive (false) に変えます
Now this code will be called
これで、2D トリガーコライダーが
every time we touch a
接触されるたびに
2D trigger collider.
このコードが呼び出されます
We're given a reference to the collider we touch
Other で、接触するコライダーへの参照を
in "other",
取得します
we test it's tag and if
その tag をテストし
the tag is the same as the
tag が
string value Pickup we will
文字列の値 PickUp と等しければ
take the other game object and
そのother ゲームオブジェクトを取得し
we will called SetActive (false)
ゲームオブジェクトをディアクティベートする
which will deactivate that game object.
SetActive (false) を呼び出します
Let's save the script and return to Unity
エラーをチェックするために
to check for errors.
スクリプトを保存してUnity に戻りましょう
The first thing we need to do is
最初にやることは
to set the Tag Value
Pickup プレハブの
for our Pickup prefab.
Tag の値を設定することです
Navigate to the Prefabs folder
Prefabs フォルダーに移動し
and highlight the Pickup prefab
Project ウィンドウの
in the project window.
Pickup プレハブをハイライトします
With the Pickup highlighted click on the
Pickup をハイライトしたままで
Tag List at the top of the inspector.
Inspector の最上部の Tag リストをクリックします
We'll see that the Pickup
プロジェクトの一部として
tag has been predefined
Pickup のタグはすでに準備されていることが
as part of the project.
分かります
If we needed to define and additional
Tag を
tag we could choose
追加する場合は
Add Tag.
Add Tag を選択します
This opens the Tags And Layers panel.
このようにして Tags & Layers パネルが開きます
Here we can hit the + button
+ ボタンを押すと
to add a new tag to our
新しい Tag がリストに
list of tags.
加えられます
To delete a tag highlight it
Tag を削除するには、ハイライトして
and hit -
－ ボタンを押します
Next highlight the Pickup prefab
次に Pickup プレハブをハイライトして
and let's assign the
Tag メニューを使って
Pickup tag to it
Pickup タグを
using the Tag menu.
割り当てましょう
Select Pickup.
Pickup を選びます
Now through the power of prefabs
さて、プレハブの利便性を使って
if we highlight a Pickup in
Hierarchy で
the hierarchy we'll see
Pickup をハイライトすると
that it too has
それも Pickup と
been tagged Pickup.
タグ付けされていることが分かります
Now let's test our game.
では、ゲームをテストしてみましょう
Save the scene and enter play mode.
シーンを保存してプレイモードにします
Okay, our tag is set to
タグは Pickup に設定されているのに
Pickup but we're still colliding
まだ、Pickup オブジェクトと
with the Pickup objects.
衝突しています
Just like we are with the walls.
まるで、壁のようです
So let's exit play mode.
プレイモードを終了しましょう
Before we discuss why we are
なぜPickup オブジェクトを取得せずにむしろ
bouncing off the Pickup objects rather than
跳ね返ってしまうのかを考える前に
picking them up we need to have a
Unity の物理システムについて
brief discussion about Unity's physics system.
簡単に説明します
Let's look at one of our pickups
Pickup と Player を
and our Player.
見てみましょう
As an aside, we can select two or
余談ですが、複数のゲームオブジェクトを
more game objects at the same time
同時に選択し
and inspect them all.
まとめて Inspector で見られます
We do this by holding down the command key
これを行うには Mac で Commandキーを
on Mac or the control key on Windows
Windows ではCtrl キーを押しながら
and selecting the game objects.
ゲームオブジェクトを選択します
When we select multiple objects
複数のオブジェクトを選ぶとき
note how the inspector changes
Inspector がどのように変化して
to show the common components
選んだオブジェクトの共通コンポーネントと
and property values of the selected game objects.
プロパティー値を表示するかに注目してください
The inspector also allows for
Inspector では
multi-object editing.
複数オブジェクト編集もできます
Using multi-object editing
複数オブジェクト編集を利用して
I'm going to disable the sprite renderer
プレイヤーの UFO と
on both the Player's UFO
選択した Pickup のスプライトレンダラーを
and the selected pickup with a single click.
1 クリックで両方とも無効にします
This leaves us with the two green
これによって2 つのオブジェクトの
outlines of the 2D collider
2D コライダーエリアの
areas for these two objects.
緑色の枠が残ります
So how do collisions work
それでは、Unityの 2D 物理エンジンで
in Unity's 2D physics engine?
どのように衝突は作用するのでしょうか
The 2D physics engine does not
2D 物理エンジンでは
allow two 2D collider
2D コライダーのエリアが
areas to overlap.
互いに重なることはできません
Remember how the Player was ejected
前回、どうやって
from the middle of the background sprite
Background スプライトの真ん中から Player を消したか
in our previous lesson.
思い出してください
When the 2D physics engine detects
2D 物理エンジンが
that any two or more
フレームに複数の2D コライダーが
2D colliders will overlap that frame
重なっているのを検知すると
the 2D physics engine will look at the
2D 物理エンジンはオブジェクトを見て
objects and analyse their speed,
そのスピード
rotation and shape
回転、形を分析し
and calculate a collision.
衝突を計算します
One of the major factors in this calculation
この計算の主要な因子の 1 つは
is whether the 2D colliders
その 2D コライダーは静的か動的か
are static or dynamic.
ということです
Static colliders are usually
静的なコライダーは通常
none moving parts of our scene
シーンの動かない部分にあります
like the walls, the floor,
たとえば、壁、床
or other parts of the scenery.
その他の風景部分などです
Dynamic colliders are things that move,
動的コライダーは動くものに使われます
like the Player's UFO,
たとえばプレイヤーの UFO や
or a car.
車などのように
When calculating a collision
衝突の計算において
the static geometry will not
静的な形状は
be affected by the collision.
衝突の影響を受けません
But the dynamic objects will be.
しかし、動的なオブジェクトは影響されます
In our case the Player's UFO
私たちのケースでは、Player の UFO は
is dynamic, or moving geometry,
動的、つまり動く形状で
and it is bouncing off the static
Pickup の静的形状から
geometry of the pickups
跳ね返ります
just as it bounces off the static geometry
ちょうど、壁の静的な形状から跳ね返るのと
of the walls.
同じように
However the 2D physics engine
ただし、2D 物理エンジンでは
can allow the penetration
2D コライダーエリアの侵入や
or overlap of 2D collider areas.
重複が可能です
When it does this the 2D physics
これらが起こっても 2D 物理エンジンは
engine still calculates the 2D
2D コライダーエリアを計算し
collider areas and keeps track
コライダーの重複を
of the collider overlap
追跡しつづけます
but it doesn't physically act
ただし、重複しているオブジェクト上では
on the overlapping objects.
物理的に動作しません
It doesn't cause a collision.
それは衝突を引き起こしません
We do this by making our
ここでは、2D コライダーを
2D colliders in to triggers,
トリガーか2D Trigger コライダーに
or 2D Trigger Colliders.
することで実現します
When we make our colliders in to a trigger
コライダーをトリガーにすると
we can detect the contact with
その 2D トリガーとの接触は
that 2D trigger through the
2DOnTriggerイベントメッセージによって
2DOnTrigger event messages.
検出されます
When a 2D collider is a trigger
2D コライダーをトリガーにすると
we can do clever things like
気の利いた使い方ができます
place a trigger in the middle of a doorway
例えば、アドベンチャーゲームで
in for example an adventure game,
トリガーを入口の真ん中に置き
and when the player enters the
プレイヤーが入るとミニマップが更新し
mini map updates and a message plays
「あなたは、この部屋を発見しました」
'you have discovered this room'.
というメッセージが出たり
Or every time our player walks
または、プレイヤーがあるエリアに侵入するたびに
in to an area a sound plays
プレイヤーがトリガーを通過して
because the player has walked through a trigger.
音が鳴ったりするなどです
For more information on 2DOnCollision
2DOnCollision と2DOnTrigger メッセージ
and 2DOnTrigger messages
に関する詳しい情報は
see the lessons linked below.
下のリンクを参照してください
We are using OnTriggerEnter2D in our code
ここでは OnCollisionEnter2D でなく
rather than OnCollisionEnter2D,
OnTriggerEnter2D を使用します
so we need to change our collider
そのため、コライダー 2D エリアを
2D areas in to trigger areas.
トリガーエリアに変更することが必要です
Let's select the prefab asset
Prefab アセットを選択し
and look at the circle collider 2D component.
Circle Collider 2D コンポーネントを表示します
I'm going to reactivate the two sprite renderers
ここで、2 つのスプライトレンダラーを再アクティベートし
and highlight the Pickup prefab.
Pickup プレハブをハイライトします
In the Circle Collider 2D component
Circle Collider 2D コンポーネントに
we see a property called Is Trigger.
Is Trigger というプロパティーがあります
Let's set this to True.
これを True に設定しましょう
Now let's enter play mode and test.
さて、プレイモードにしてテストしてみましょう
Excellent, let's exit play mode.
良いですね、プレイモードを終了します
So far everything looks great.
ここまで、全部うまくいっていますが
But we have one issue.
1 つ問題があります
We've made a small mistake,
私たちは 1 つ小さなミスをしてしまいました
which is related to how Unity
それは、Unity の 2D 物理計算の
optimises it's 2D physics.
最適化に関連しています
When using 2D physics all
2D 物理計算を使用する場合
of the static, or non-moving
すべての静的、または動かないコライダーは
colliders are calculated as
単体として
a single body.
計算されます
This increases performance.
こうすると、パフォーマンスが向上します
If we move a collider that the engine
エンジンが動くことを予想していない
is not expecting to move
コライダーを動かすと
the static collider or all our
その静的コライダーや動かないオブジェクトを
non-moving objects will have to be recalculated.
再度計算する必要がでてきます
If we do this every frame we risk
これをすべてのフレームで行うと
our game losing performance.
ゲームのパフォーマンスが悪くなる恐れがあります
Where we've made our mistake is
アイテムを回転させることで
by rotating our pickups.
間違いをしてしまったのです
We need to indicate to Unity
それらを動かす前に
which 2D colliders are dynamic
どの 2D コライダーが動的であるかを
before we move them.
Unity に示す必要があります
We do this by using the
私たちは、それを
rigidbody2D component.
Rigidbody2D コンポーネントで行います
Any game object with a 2D collider
2D コライダーと Rigidbody2D をもつ
and a rigidbody2D
ゲームオブジェクトはすべて
is considered dynamic.
動的とみなされます
Any game object with a 2D collider
2D コライダーを持ち
but no rigidbody2D
Rigidbody2D をもたないゲームオブジェクトは
is expected to be static.
すべて静的とみなされます
Currently our Pickup game objects
現在 Pickup ゲームオブジェクトには
have a circle collider but
Circle Collider が設定されていますが
no rigidbody2D.
Rigidbody2D はありません
So Unity is recreating
そのため Unity は各フレームで
the collider's for the pickups and walls
アイテムと壁のコライダーを
each frame.
再作成します
The solution is to add a rigidbody2D
解決するには Rigidbody2D を
to the Pickup objects.
Pickup オブジェクトに設定します
Let's enter play mode and test.
プレイモードにしてテストしてみましょう
As we can see, our Pickups fall off the screen.
ご覧のように Pickup　が画面から落ちてしまいます
Gravity pulls them down and
重力によって下に引っ張られるのです
because they are triggers they
しかも、トリガーであるため
don't collide with the walls.
壁と衝突しません
If we look at the rigidbody2D component
Rigidbody2D コンポーネントを見ると
we see that we could simply set
Gravity Scale を 0 に
Gravity Scale to 0,
簡単に設定できたことに気づきます
which would prevent the Pickups
それで Pickup が落ちることを
from falling downwards.
防げたはずです
This is only a partial solution however.
ただし、これは部分的な解決策にすぎません
If we did this even
もし、そうしたとして Pickup が
though our Pickups would not respond to
重力に影響を受けなくなったとしても
gravity they would still respond
まだ、物理的な力に
to physics forces.
影響されていたでしょう
There's a better solution.
もっと良い解決法があります
That is to select Is Kinematic.
それはIs Kinematic を有効にすることです
When we do this we set this
これを行うと
rigidbody2D component
Rigidbody2D コンポーネントを
to be a kinematic 2D rigidbody.
キネマティックの 2D Rigidbody にすることができます
A kinematic 2D rigidbody
キネマティック 2D Rigidbody は
will not react to physics forces
物理的な力に反応しませんが
and can be animated and moved
Transform によって
by it's transform.
アニメーションと移動を行えます
This is great for everything from objects
これは、すべてのオブジェクトに有効です
with colliders like elevators and
エレベーターや移動するプラットフォームなどのような
moving platforms to objects
コライダーを持つオブジェクトから
with triggers, like our collectables,
作成中のアイテムのようにトリガーが設定され
that need to be animated or moved
Transform によって、アニメーションや
by their transform.
移動をするものまで OK です
For more information on the rigidbody2D
Rigidbody2D と Is Kinematicに関する情報は
and Is Kinematic
下のリンクのレッスンを
see the lessons linked below.
ご覧ください
Let's save our scene and enter play mode to test.
シーンを保存し、プレイモードにしてテストしてみましょう
Now our behaviour is identical
今度は、ビヘイビアは
and performant.
思った通りになりました
So static 2D colliders shouldn't move,
静的な 2D コライダーは
like walls and floors,
壁や床のように不動で
dynamic 2D colliders can move
動的 2D コライダーは動きますが
but should have a rigidbody2D attached.
ただし Rigidbody2D がアタッチされるべきだったのです
Standard 2D rigidbodies like our
この Player のような標準の2D rigidbody は
Player are moved using 2D physics forces.
2D の物理的な力を使用して動きます
Kinematic 2D rigidbodies are
キネマティック 2D rigidbody は
moved using their transform.
transform によって動きます
In the next assignment we will count our
次回は
collectable objects and make a
アイテムを数え
simple UI to display
スコアとメッセージを表示する
our score and messages.
簡単な UI を作成します